markosweb.com 2011-05-28

# SmartViper Policy

INFORMATION COLLECTION AND PRIVACY POLICY. 

This information collection and privacy policy shows how we get information from http://www.smartviper.com site (the "Site") and controls the information you give us. The policy doesn’t control the entries or edits you submit to the Site. That information is dealt with singly at this link Terms and Conditions of Use. Any changed and revised information collection and privacy policy shall come into force right after posting on the Site. 

In case of questions or concerns concerning this statement, users can contact Smartviper.com or send mail to Website Administrator (see mail at the bottom of this page). We will try to respond to every inquiry. But the volume of inquiries we receive is very high so we may respond to your inquiry after a while. 

SmartViper obtains information concerning websites from the public "whois" databases which domain name registries and registrars publish on the Internet. We also receive information concerning websites from other public sources and from the "about us" section of websites. Then we make that information available, together with a link to the websites, screenshots, and logos one centralized place of the Site. We also put a map that is some kind of a spatial representation of otherwise public information. Everybody can build this map using the "about us" tool and one of innumerable free web mapping applications available in the Internet. As we only make available from the Site information which is publicly available, we may make available contact information for a website. Users may freely edit and add data concerning websites. 

If you don’t wish our bot to collect information about your website just follow the instructions on the SmartViper:Bot page. 

Control of User Provided/Edited Posts: 

Users of SmartViper can freely edit entries. Here we don’t control the identity of any user who provides information or make edits. An "Owner Contributed Information" feature will allow you as the owner of a website to control the basic information about that website. In any case you should know that we haven’t controlled information and you should control this information yourself before relying on it. 

SmartViper Respects Intellectual Property Rights: 

SmartViper respects the intellectual property rights of third parties. It will never be involved in measures which contain copyright or trademark violation. SmartViper is meant for providing free information concerning domain names and related websites. Here, you can find educational, critical and accurate information about websites. We don’t publish texts or images from a site with the purpose of their providing. We just make them available to provide information about the site itself. We can’t precisely provide full information about a site without watching the information from the site itself. 

SmartViper presents information which may not be entitled to copyright defense in the first instance. Display of smaller thumbnail-size images and of public text falls under "fair use". Copyright and trademark law include exclusions for "fair use". Fair use is a statutorily recognized exception to copyright law. United States courts apply a four factor test to define whether a use constitutes "fair use" under copyright law. According to this test, SmartViper’s use constitutes fair use. First of all, SmartViper’s use of the information differs from the initial expressive purpose of the information. SmartViper has collected this information in a single place with the aim of providing knowledge concerning domain names and websites, open for editing by the user. 

Secondly, SmartViper doesn’t use the expressive value of text or images we make available. We use the text and images in order to inform users about the domain names and website where the complete text and full images may be found. Thirdly, the restricted or reduced use of the texts and images is compatible with transformative purpose of SmartViper. And finally, SmartViper doesn’t harm the market with the underlying data. Reproducing data about your website we are simply raising potential exposure for your website. Thus SmartViper’s use of the information constitutes fair use after application of the fair use test. You can watch additional information and discussion about SmartViper’s position on fair use and intellectual property policy at Intellectual Property Policy. 

If you don’t want to include information from your site, please opt-out consistent with the above instructions. 

What Information We Gather And How We Use This Information: 

We don’t gather any Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") about users from the Site unless you decide to provide it to us. This means that you can visit most parts of the Site without notifying us who you are or opening any PII about yourself. But if you edit any information available on the Site we log your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This information will be showed together with the edited information and is publicly a vailable. Your IP address can be used by the third parties to know more information about you. 

a) Your Log-in/Registration Information. In order to register or log-in to use the Site, you may be required to provide PII. Some log-in information will be showed together with the content you submit to the Site. This will be clearly disclosed to you during registration. Differently, any data you give as part of registration or log-in won’t be passed to anyone unless otherwise allowed by this privacy policy and will be used for that very purpose for which you give the information. 

b) Information Tracked by Cookies. During your use of the Site we may send a Cookie to your computer to ascertain your browser. Cookies help us to track and compile your browsing habits on the Site. 

How We Use This Information: We use Cookies for controlling whether you are a registered person and watching your visits to the Site. Besides we use Cookies to define the amount of visitors coming to the Site. The amount of your Cookies is also used to determine usage paths and to confer them with any demographic data you provide, but we don’t use your cookies or usage paths to identify you. Also we may use Cookies for specific advertisements to you on the Site on the basis of your browsing habits tracked by the Cookies. Most browsers have the function that allows disabling Cookies. But some of our services can’t work properly in the case of Cookies disabling. 

c) Information Tracked by Web Beacons. We may use Web Beacons concerning e-mails we may send you to let us know if you read our email. Besides we use Web Beacons to watch your browsing habits on the Site. How We Use This Information: We use Web Beacons to control the efficiency of certain communications as well as the efficiency of our marketing campaigns. We may use Web Beacons for specific advertisements to you on the Site based on your browsing habits tracked by the Web Beacons. 

d) Non-Personally Identifiable Information or Aggregated PII. We won’t use information received from server logs, Cookies and Web Beacons for your identifying unless requested by law or subpoena, or necessary to defend the security or rights of SmartViper, its customers, employees or property. Moreover, we may collect PII and create statistics on the basis of such collected data, but such collected data won’t identify you personally. How We Use This Information: SmartViper may transfer non-Personally Identifiable Information or collected PII to third parties in order to define the results a promotion, event or third party relationship, to give data to current or potential customers, or to expand your online experience. 

Data Other Companies and Advertisers Gather: 

a) Sites We Do Not Own or Operate. We may give links to third party websites which are owned or operated by other companies that are not controlled by us. Such websites may gather data about you, but we can’t control the data collection of such companies. If you visit such sites, please read the privacy policy of that website carefully concerning data collection and usage. 

b) Advertisers. SmartViper may host advertising on the Site. If during your visit to any site depicted in an advertisement you provide PII you won’t have to provide the PII to a third party. Privacy policies and practices applied by the advertiser may differ from those of SmartViper, and you should address to the advertiser's privacy policy before providing such data. Advertising partners of a third party may use cookies on the sites that allow them recognizing a user's cookie during his visit to the sites. The data that is gathered by these advertising partners via this technology isn’t personally identifiable. 

Revisions to This Policy: 

a) Notice. We promise to inform you about any material revisions or changes that may occur in our privacy policies by posting a notice on our Site. At any material revision or change to our privacy policy, you have the right cease your use of the Site. Any beforehand provided data shall be controlled by the current policy unless you personally contact us concerning your data. 

b) Assignment of Data. SmartViper may be involved in a transaction which requires it to assign any of the data controlled by this privacy policy. This may contain a sale, integration, or a transfer of all or substantially all of SmartViper's assets. So, we may transfer or assign your data to a third party, including PII. 

Children's Privacy: 

NOTE: SmartViper’s services and the Site may not be used by children under the age of 18 without the advance written approve of a parent or legal guardian. SmartViper doesn’t intentionally gather data from children under the age of 18 and does not grant its services, software and the Site to children under 18. You can find Parental Consent Form here. 

NOTE: This privacy policy is applied only to the privacy of the Site’s users. Using any part of this Site you agree with the terms in this privacy policy. 

Privacy Policy--Glossary of Terms. 

"Cookies" are small files comprising a sequence of characters which are sent to your computer by our services to uniquely identify your browser. 

"Personally Identifiable Information" or "Personal Information" or "PII" is information you provide in connection with your use of the Site: your name, address, phone number or other data that can personally identify you. This does not contain data provided to any third party sources (e.g., "whois") which is created by SmartViper. 

"Web Beacons" - a pixel tag or a clear GIF attached to an email or site and used to control the behavior of the user who visit the website or view the email.
